Guide to the American Association of University Women Portland Branch records
Oregon Historical Society Research Library
- Activities and events, 1923-2018; Series 4
  - Materials relating to 110th anniversary celebration, including historical narrative, event program, and timeline drafts, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Program and historical narrative for 110th anniversary (digital files), 2015
  - Reproductions of brochures, publication covers, and newspaper article with explanatory captions, possibly made for 110th anniversary celebration, 1956-1978; circa 2015 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Itinerary for African educators program, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Records and flyer for auctions, 1997 December; 2001 December (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mailing relating to Portland and Beaverton Branches' holiday auction for AAUW Educational Foundation, circa 2005 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Records and ephemera relating to book sales, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clippings about national AAUW convention in Portland, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Records for national AAUW convention in Portland, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
  - Posters and displays for convention, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence and records relating to Christmas teas, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Program and flyer for Educational Foundation brunch, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Guestbook pages for Founders Day tea, 1949 March 4 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Records relating to life insurance forums, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - National Art Week award for distinguished participation, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Records and samples relating to notepaper fundraising project, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Flyers, programs, and ticket for events, circa 1970-1988; 2014-2017 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Brunch and luncheon meeting flyers and programs, 2001; 2009-2016 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Schedule of programs for 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Records, displays, and flyers for luncheons, conventions, and other events (digital files), 2013-2018
- Newsletters, 1925-2023; Series 5
  - Issues of "Calendar", 1925-1956 (Box 6, Folder 26-35)
  - Issues of Free-Time School newsletter, "Free Timer", 1933 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Issues of "Calendar"; issues of "News and Events", 1956 October-1957 January; 1957 February-May (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Issues of "Calendar 1957-1958", 1957 October-1958 May (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Issues of "1958-59 Calendar"; untitled newsletter issues, 1958 October-1959 May; 1959 October-1960 June (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Untitled newsletter issues, 1960 October-1963 May (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Issues of "Portland Branch News", 1963 September-1967 May (Box 6, Folder 40-41)
  - Issues of "Portland Branch News", 1967 September-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1-13)
  - Issues of "Portland Branch News"; issues of "Soundings", 1986 September-1987 May; 1987 September-1988 May (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Issues of "Soundings", 1988 September-1992 May (Box 7, Folder 15-16)
  - Issues of "Rose City Reporter", 1997-2019 (Box 7, Folder 17-26)
  - Issues of "Rose City Reporter" (digital files), 2006-2023
- Parent organization records and memorabilia, 1922-2018; Series 6
  Access to audio and video materials and to digital files on CD in this series require specialized equipment. Digital files not on CD are available upon request. Contact library staff for assistance.
  - AAUW of Oregon, 1923-2018; Subseries 1
    - Compiled records, correspondence, and clippings about division's history, 1932-1987 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Report on division's history, "The First Quarter Century", 1950 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Compiled records and information about local chapters within the division, Ashland through Reedsport, circa 1945-1981 (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
    - Compiled records and information about local chapters within the division, Roseburg through Woodburn, 1947-1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Lists of presidents, conventions, and meetings, circa 1970; 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Incomplete index of bound volumes of records, circa 1995 (Box 19)
    - Bylaws and policies (bound volume), 1928-1990 (Box 19)
    - Directories (3 bound volumes), 1932-1991 (Box 19)
    - Meeting minutes (2 bound volumes), 1923-1990 (Box 19)
    - Meeting minutes (3 bound volumes), 1953-1989 (Box 20)
    - Meeting minutes and related records, 1989-2007 (Box 8, Folder 3-10)
    - Officer reports, 2017 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Certificates for contributions to AAUW Educational Foundation Oregon Century Club, 2006 April 28 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Directory and expense form, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Outline of priorities, 2016 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Recommendation presented at state conference with handwritten notes, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Registration form for Oregon AAUW Online Branch (blank), 2017 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Records, correspondence, publications, and clippings relating to first state fellowship, circa 1926-1937; 1928 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - AAUW of Oregon fellowship records and memorabilia, 1930-1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Information and correspondence about June Philpott Endowment; reproduction negative of 1952 photograph of June Philpott, 1973; 1981 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Margaret Comstock Snell Fellowship records, 1933-1950 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Records, newsletters, clippings, and brochures about public policy and legislation, 1992-1995 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Registration form for Lobby Day (digital file), 2016
    - Notice about public policy discussion (digital file), 2018 January
    - Public policy brochure, circa 2015 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Report, "Visiting the Hostile Hallways of Oregon Schools", 2001 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Statements against Measure 9 and for Measure 6, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Materials relating to special projects and activism for women, 1943-1985 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Records and memorabilia relating to special projects for children and education, 1950-1973 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - News release about support for public education, 1984 May (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence and clippings about 50th anniversary celebration, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence and notes about 60th anniversary celebration and attached clipping, 1985; 1956 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Conference and convention records and memorabilia, 1939-1941 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Convention workbooks and programs (4 bound volumes), 1925-1983 (Box 20)
    - Convention workbooks and programs (1 bound volume), 1984-1991 (Box 21)
    - Records, program, and newsletter relating to state convention, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - State convention programs, 2011-2013 (Box 8, Folder 33-35)
    - Oregon and Washington joint state convention program, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Convention programs, 2015-2016 (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
    - Program for funds dinner at state convention, 2018 April 21 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Convention records (digital files), 2008-2016
    - Audio recordings of state convention sessions (3 microcassettes), 2005 April-May (Box 13)
    - Newsletters; treasurer's reports (1 bound volume), 1937-1956; 1925-1968 (Box 21)
    - Newsletters (1 bound volume), 1954-1979 (Box 21)
    - Newsletters (1 bound volume), 1979-1991 (Box 22)
    - Newsletters, 1980; 2016-2017 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Newsletters of North Pacific Region Branch and Hood River Branch, 1981 September; 1986 December (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - National AAUW, 1922-2015; Subseries 2
    - History of AAUW by Ruth W. Tryon, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Short film about AAUW, "Because Equity is Still an Issue", 2007; MI 10092; 1 videodiscs (DVD) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to Portland branch, 1922 May-October; 1932 September 8 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence and certificates relating to honorary life membership, 2006 December (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Directory of approved universities and colleges; membership policy book, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Membership booklet, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Leaflet about AAUW Educational Foundation, circa 1985 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Directories of named fellowships, 1958; 1970 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Directories of people honored by the AAUW Educational Foundation for donations made between 1971 and 1988, 1972-1988 (Box 8, Folder 49-50)
    - Directories of people honored by the AAUW Educational Foundation for donations made between 1988 and 2000, 1989-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Information and guidelines for archiving records, 2013-2015 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Guidelines for archiving state and branch records (digital file), 2011 October
    - Digital presentation and template files for membership drive campaign, "Keys to the Future: A Member Get a Member Campaign" (digital files on CD), 2006 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Brochure and planning book for community action, circa 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Mailing about National Program for Voluntary Action, 1970 December 4 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Public policy program for 2003-2005 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Reports, "Idealism at Work: Eighty Years of AAUW Fellowships," and "Idealism at Work: AAUW Educational Foundation Programs, 1967-1981" (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "How Schools Shortchange Girls", 1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Hostile Hallways: The AAUW Survey on Sexual Harassment in America's Schools", 1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Growing Smart: What's Working for Girls in Schools", 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Girls Can!", 1996 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Girls in the Middle: Working to Succeed in School", 1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Gender Gaps: Where Schools Still Fail Our Children", 1998 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Separated by Sex: A Critical Look at Single-Sex Education for Girls", 1998 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Gaining a Foothold: Women's Transitions Through Work and College, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Voices of a Generation: Teenage Girls on Sex, School, and Self", 1999 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Tech Savvy: Educating Girls in the New Computer Age", 2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - AAUW Legal Advocacy Fund report, "A License for Bias: Sex Discrimination, Schools, and Title IX", 2000 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation publication, "Community Coalitions Manual", 2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "The Third Shift: Women Learning Online", 2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Beyond the 'Gender Wars': A Conversation about Girls, Boys, and Education", 2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation report, "Women at Work", 2003 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation and AAUW Legal Advocacy Fund report, "Tenure Denied: Cases of Sex Discrimination in Academia", 2004 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation video, "Girls Can!", 1994; MI 10086; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation video, "Girls in the Middle: Working to Succeed in School", 1996; MI 10087; 1 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - AAUW Educational Foundation video presentation about economic inequities women face (used at April 2006 conference), 2005; MI 10088; 1 videodiscs (DVD) (Box 15, Folder 6)